A Guide to the Jeff Trollinger Papers: Records of the Sexual Minorities Commission and Other Voices Chorus, 1990-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Scrapbooks 1990-2004, undated (Box 1-7)
  - Scrapbook 2, original 1990-1994, undated (Box 4)
    - Well, I'm out. Deal with it. By Mark Morrison, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 March 23. (Frame 4:69)
    - St. Mary's Catholic Church, Blacksburg, VA brochure, 1994. (Frame 4:70)
    - Gay group rates Wyatt, Edwards, Harris highly Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 May 2. (Frame 4:71)
    - California gets first openly gay candidate The Associated Press, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 May 12. (Frame 4:72)
    - Robb takes a strong stand in favor of homosexual rights The Washington Post, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 May 10. (Frame 4:73)
    - Judge reinstates lesbian officer New York Times News Service, 1994 June 2. (Frame 4:74)
    - Supervisors petitioned to deny library money until book's removed by Brian Kelley, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 June 15. (Frame 4:75)
    - Family portraits: Photographer discovers the ties that bind in gay America by Sibella Connor Richmond Times-Dispatch 1994 June 8. (Frame 4:76)
    - Doonesbury by Garry Trudeau, 8 cartoons, undated. (Frame 4:77)
    - VHDA loan rule is altered by Virginia Churn, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:78)
    - Under the rainbow photograph, undated. (Frame 4:79)
    - How many books for bonfire? letter to the editor by Thaddeus Riddle, Blacksburg, undated. (Frame 4:80)
    - Lesbian mom wins custody by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1994 June 22 (Frame 4:81)
    - Gay activists salute ruling by Peter Bacque, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:82)
    - Lesbian joins foes of father's measure The Associated Press, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch (Frame 4:83)
    - Lesbian case on track to top court by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:84)
    - Lesbian reunited with son by Greg Schneider, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 June 22. (Frame 4:85)
    - Gays celebrate roots of cultural movement, change by Mike Doring, Chicago Tribune, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News, undated. (Frame 4:86)
    - Lesbian-custody case headed for high court, undated. (Frame 4:87)
    - Opponents raise stink over syntax by Leslie Taylor, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 July 1. (Frame 4:88)
    - Fatalistic attitude leads gays back to unsafe sex Seattle Post-Intelligencer, undated. (Frame 4:89)
    - 'World' has a realistic chance this time by Tom Shales, undated. (Frame 4:90)
    - For Better or For Worse by Lynn Johnston, 2002 April, undated. (Frame 4:91)
    - 2 gay Navy officers face hearings by Bill Geroux, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1994 July 12. (Frame 4:92)
    - Navy board: Discharge gay sailor by Bill Geroux, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:93)
    - Gay sailor continues fight to keep his job by Bill Geroux, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:94)
    - Episcopal sexuality statement debated from Staff, Wire Dispatches, undated. (Frame 4:95)
    - Charlottesville bans gay discrimination, undated. (Frame 4:96)
    - Contentious Issue, undated. (Frame 4:97)
    - Drafts leaked, undated. (Frame 4:98)
    - 'Roommate' debate continues New River Valley Bureau, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 November 4. (Frame 4:99)
    - Announcement: The Montgomery County Council on Human Relations presents a forum on Should the book, Daddy's Roommate, be kept in the children's section of the Montgomery-Floyd Regional Library, 1994 November 7. (Frame 4:100)
    - Tense forum held on 'Daddy's Roommate' by Stephen Foster, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 November 7. (Frame 4:101)
    - Mary Washington faculty supports covering partners by Christine Neuberger, Richmond Times-Dispatch 1994 November 3. (Frame 4:102)
    - Sex orientation, biology linked The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:103)
    - Bishops don't act on issues involving gays by Ed Briggs, Richmond Times-Dispatch undated. (Frame 4:104)
    - All in the family by Bill Lohmann, Richmond Times-Dispatch undated. (Frame 4:105)
    - Straight isn't the only path to laughter by David Patrick Stearns, USA Today, undated. (Frame 4:106)
    - Despite struggle, gay officer doesn't regret disclosure by Leslie Taylor, undated. (Frame 4:107)
    - When a parent is homosexual Lynn Minton Reports: Fresh Voices, Parade Magazine 1994 September 11. (Frame 4:108)
    - Corporate vendors find it pays to be gay-friendly by Greg Dalton, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:109)
    - National Coming Out Day observances Blacksburg, undated. (Frame 4:110)
    - Ruling narrows military's gay policy The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:111)
    - Brochure-St. Mary's Catholic Church (Blacksburg, VA), undated. (Frame 4:112)
    - Clinton yields to anti-gay bigotry by Robert A. Bernstein, undated. (Frame 4:113)
    - Neighbors bring AIDS specter home by Kristen Kammerer, correspondent, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 December 1. (Frame 4:114)
    - The wrath of-God? by Jeffery B. Connor, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1994 December 9. (Frame 4:115)
    - Ruling due on bar to gay rights laws The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:116)
    - Justices take gay-rights case Knight-Ridder-Tribune, 1995 February 22. (Frame 4:117)
    - Aviator gets Navy medal despite expulsion move Washington, undated. (Frame 4:118)
    - Gay minister still fasting, demanding Robertson meeting The Associated Press, Roanoke Times and World-News 1995 February 23. (Frame 4:119)
    - Rally held to support jailed gay rights activist Norfolk, undated. (Frame 4:120)
    - Louganis reveals AIDS The Associated Press undated. (Frame 4:121)
    - Louganis' silence wasn't golden by Jim Litke, undated. (Frame 4:122)
    - Louganis: 'All I could do was cry' The Associated Press, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News 1995 February 24. (Frame 4:123)
    - Secret is out-media mogul left her for him by Rick Hampson, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:124)
    - Speaker's sister pays a visit The Associated Press, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:125)
    - 'Don't ask, don't tell' challenged The Associated Press, printed in Roanoke Times and World-News 1995 March 14. (Frame 4:126)
    - It's time for gays to join the community of faith by Betsy Wright, The Virginian-Pilot and the Ledge-Star, 1994 March 4. (Frame 4:127)
    - Vigil for activist draws hundreds by Steve Stone, undated. (Frame 4:128)
    - How to make gays a part of church life by Betsy Wright, The Virginian-Pilot and the Ledge-Star, undated. (Frame 4:129)
    - Judge rebuffs military Los Angeles Times undated. (Frame 4:130)
    - Lesbian mom ruled unfit to keep child The Herald, 1995 April 22. (Frame 4:131)
    - Court rules lesbian mother unfit, denies custody of son by Warren Fiske, undated. (Frame 4:132)
    - Virginia gets away with kidnapping, undated (Frame 4:133)
    - Court lets parade sponsor exclude homosexual group The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:134)
    - Senate bill protects gays in the workplace by Debbie Howlett, USA Today, 1995 June 15. (Frame 4:133)
    - 'Don't ask, don't tell' is upheld in Va. case from Wire Reports printed in USA Today 1995 June 15. (Frame 4:134)
    - Doonesbury by Garry Trudeau, undated. (Frame 4:135)
    - Methodists oppose weaker policy on gays by Cody Lowe, The Roanoke Times, undated. (Frame 4:136)
    - Housing Authority rules may violate federal law by Virginia Churn Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:137)
    - Cartoon, untitled, undated (Frame 4:138)
    - Note on Church Teaching Concerning Homosexual People origins: CNS documentary service, Vol. 24: No.45, 1995 April 27 (Frame 4:139)
    - More Options for Gay Travelers by Betsy Wade, undated. (Frame 4:140)
    - 'When a parent is homosexual' Readers respond Lynn Minton Reports Fresh Voices, Parade Magazine, 1995 August 27. (Frame 4:141)
    - Bon Air Presbyterians debating role of gays by Alberta Lindsey, Richmond Times-Dispatch 1996 February 18. (Frame 4:142)
    - Dole returns donation to gay GOP group The New York Times, printed in The Roanoke Times, 1995 August 27. (Frame 1:143)
    - Lobbyists call Gilmore bigot for aid in anti-gay rights belief by Mike Allen, Richmond Times-Dispatch undated. (Frame 1:144)
    - Fla. lawmakers condemn Disney policy on gays Tallahassee, Fla., undated. (Frame 4:145)
    - Paper moves gay editor from children's section Dallas, undated. (Frame 4:146)
    - At Core of Constitution: Colorado Gay Rights Case by George Will, Washington Post Writers Group, undated. (Frame 4:147)
    - Colo. ban of laws protecting gays encounters skepticism The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:148)
    - Kinky Courses re: sexuality courses taught at universities such as Yale and University of Minnesota, undated. (Frame 4:149)
    - Bill to ban gay bias gets Clinton's support New Your Times News Service, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1995 October 18. (Frame 4:150)
    - Dole says refund of gays' contribution was wrong The Associated Press, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1995 October 18. (Frame 4:151)
    - Virginia Beach has gay anti-bias policy The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:152)
    - Bottoms wants mother punished over visitation by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:153)
    - Setting the senator straight about AIDS column by Ann Landers featuring letter from Senator Jesse Helms, undated. (Frame 4:154)
    - Kay Bottoms seeks aid of daughter by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:155)
    - 'Sexuality' gene studied The Associated Press, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1995 October 31. (Frame 4:156)
    - U.S. ruling protects partnerships of gays The Baltimore Sun, 1995 December 23. (Frame 4:157)
    - Lesbian mother's visits ordered to resume by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1995 November 2. (Frame 4:158)
    - The values dilemma by Gil Klein, Media General News Service, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1995 December 10 (Frame 4:159)
    - A Barrage of Questions About Homosexuals in the Nation's Military by Ross Mackenzie, undated. (Frame 4:160)
    - High court in N.Y. rules gays have right to adopt, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:161)
    - VHDA makes loans 'family' affair, by Virginia Churn, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:162)
    - Theory about lesbian moms is deflated, The Associated Press undated. (Frame 4:163)
    - Gay cleric renews criticism, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:164)
    - Gay marriage target of bills, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:165)
    - Reform rabbis back homosexual marriages, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:166)
    - Survey finds freshmen's abortion support is down, undated (Frame 4:167)
    - Bottoms case back in court today, by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:168)
    - Lesbian mother takes the stand, by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:169)
    - High court strikes anti-gay-rights law, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:170)
    - Wanted: Gay Faculty, by Pamela Walsh, The Northeastern News, Norteastern University, 1994 October. (Frame 4:171)
    - Gays ruling may not affect housing rule, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:172)
    - Bottoms to appeal 2nd ruling, by Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:173)
    - Episcopal court dismisses heresy charges 7-1, Knight-Ridder Newspapers, undated. (Frame 4:174)
    - Reed rebutted as he asks allies for kinder tone on gays, Clinton, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:175)
    - Bork seat held, not his values, by David Savage, Los Angeles Times and Washington Post News Service, undated. (Frame 4:176)
    - Compromise Could Yield Gay Couples Benefits Without Approbation, by William Safire, undated. (Frame 4:177)
    - Study links fingerprints, male homosexuality, The Associated Press, 1994 December 26. (Frame 4:178)
    - Tapping gently the gay market, by Jeannine Stein, Los Angeles Times and Washington Post News Service, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 June 9. (Frame 4:179)
    - Homosexual Marriage Is Not Needed for Civility, by Suzanne Fields, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:180)
    - In Colorado 'Gay Rights' Case, High Court Mangled the Constitution by George Will, Washington Post Writers Group, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 May 23. (Frame 4:181)
    - Don't Blame Homosexuals for Threat to American Family, by Stephen Chapman, Creators Syndicate, Inc., printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 May 23. (Frame 4:182)
    - Gay dimension to spiritual life, by John McNeill, undated. (Frame 4:183)
    - They're the moms, story by Paul Woody, photo illustrations by Stuart T. Wagner, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 August 18. (Frame 4:184)
    - State not alone in regulating sexual matters, by Michael Paul Williams, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 July 1. (Frame 4:185)
    - Doonesbury by Garry Trudeau, undated. (Frame 4:186)
    - Gay Virginian trusts in Clinton, party, by Tyler Whitley, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:187)
    - Bottoms can take son home, by Tom Campbell and Deborah Kelly, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:188)
    - Lesbian mother drops custody fight, by Tom Campbell, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:189)
    - Lifestyles come in different varieties, Dear Abby column, Abigail Van Buren, 1996 September 26. (Frame 4:190)
    - Custody ruling reflects intolerance, letters to the editor regarding Bottoms custody case Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:191)
    - Homosexuals have a hard row to hoe, by Ann Landers, correspondence column undated. (Frame 4:192)
    - Senate ponders gay-rights job bill, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:193)
    - Defending Marriage, undated. (Frame 4:194)
    - Hawaii legislators move to address gay marriages, Honolulu, undated. (Frame 4:195)
    - IBM covers gay partners, New York, undated. (Frame 4:196)
    - Defending Marriage, Richmond Times-Dispatch 1996 September 15. (Frame 4:197)
    - Lesbian lifestyle didn't undermine woman's dreams, by Alberta Lindsey, Richmond Times-Dispatch 1996 August 10. (Frame 4:198)
    - Doonesbury Garry Trudeau, undated. (Frame 4:199)
    - Democratic incumbents win in Hawaii, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:200)
    - Fuzzy line divides practice of 'outing,' judgment of the public's right to know, by Ellen Debenport, undated. (Frame 4:201)
    - House stamps disapproval on homosexual marriages, Scripps Howard News Service undated. (Frame 4:202)
    - Gay job rights, marriages rejected, from Wire Reports, printed in Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:203)
    - Robb sees gay-rights foes as regressive, by Peter Hardin, Times-Dispatch Washington Correspondent, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 September 11. (Frame 4:204)
    - Shades of President Johnson, by Peter Hardin, Times-Dispatch Washington Correspondent, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 September 16. (Frame 4:205)
    - Gays protest Clinton signing, The Associated Press, undated. (Frame 4:206)
    - Strict Definition of Marriage Has Met the Test of History by Jeff Jacoby, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 July 21. (Frame 4:207)
    - Gay pride event gets Candace Gingrich by Peter Bacque, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:208)
    - Candlelight vigil honors slain gays, lesbians; opens festival, by Gary Roberston, Richmond Times-Dispatch, undated. (Frame 4:209)
    - A festival of pride, politics, by Mike Allen, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1996 September 23. (Frame 4:210)
    - I Can Be Fully Myself - Gay and Christian, by Laurie Goodstein, The Washington Post, 1996 September 29. (Frame 4:211)
    - Gay denominations are growing nationwide, The Washington Post 1996 September 29. (Frame 4:212)
    - Report to the commissioner to study homosexuality to general council of ministries of United Methodist church, 1991 August 24. (Frame 4:213)
    - Ignorance Is Not Bliss, by Eric Marcus, Newsweek, 1993 July 5. (Frame 4:124)
  - Scrapbook 3, Original 1990-1993 (Box 5)
    - Protecting 'sexual orientation,' letter to the editor, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5::1)
    - New resolutions, by Brian McConnell, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5:2)
    - Policies pass first reading, Collegiate Times undated. (Frame 5:3)
    - Council revises policy, by Stephen Foster, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5:4)
    - Sexual orientation added to resolution, Collegiate Times, 1991 February 14. (Frame 5:5)
    - Advocates: Gay soldiers fighting war on 2 fronts, The News Messenger, Christiansburg, VA, 1991 March 6. (Frame 5:6)
    - Announcement-National Coming Out Day, 1990 October 11. (Frame 5:7)
    - Gay-bashing in the name of the Lord, by Bryan Walker, undated. (Frame 5:8)
    - Facing Homosexuality, undated. (Frame 5:9)
    - Announcement-Gay and Lesbian Pride National Coming Out Day Rally; Virginia Tech's Gay, Lesbian and Bisexual Student Organization, 1990 October 11. (Frame 5:10)
    - Coming Out, by Howard Simpson, Collegiate Times 1990 October 12. (Frame 5:11)
    - Letters to the editor, Collegiate Times 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:12-22)
      - 'Committing what is shameful, 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:12)
      - 'Love thy neighbor' stressed, by Jeff Trollinger 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:13)
      - Professional insults, by Jim Magner 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:14)
      - Homecoming rivalry, by J.D. LaFalce 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:15)
      - Ignorance dispelled by reason, by Don Baker 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:16)
      - Accepting lifestyles, by Forrest Tiffany 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:17)
      - Internal honesty, by Vincent S. Randall 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:18)
      - Choosing own beliefs, by Andy Leynes and Kent Pearson 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:19)
      - Ambiguity cited in scripture, by Newton S. Lee 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:20)
      - Homecoming uncomfortable, by Gretchen Bright 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:21)
      - Naturally impulse, by Dana C. Harbin 1990 October 23 (Frame 5:22)
    - Population Control, by Brian McConnell, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5:23)
    - Finding real issue of concern, letter to the editor, Collegiate Times, 1990 November 2. (Frame 5:24)
    - Tales of the Heart: In this special Valentine's Day section, the Collegiate Times lets people tell the stories of their most romantic moments. Enjoy the stories and have a happy Valentine's Day, Includes story of Paul and Kevin Collegiate Times, 1991 February 12. (Frame 5:25)
    - SGA presidential candidates debate, by Danielle Corso, Collegiate Times, 1991 February 22. (Frame 5:26)
    - Platforms for Student Government Association Offices, by Missy Byrne, Brian McConnell, Collegiate Times, 1991 February 26. (Frame 5:27)
    - Elect McConnell, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5:28)
    - 'Unified University' takes SGA elections, by Angela Lobb, Collegiate Times, 1991 March 1. (Frame 5:29)
    - Tally reveals clear-cut win for president, by Stephen Foster, Collegiate Times, undated. (Frame 5:30)
    - Methodist Congregation Blesses Lesbian Couple's Union, by Lynda Richardson, The Washington Post, 1990 May 11. (Frame 5:31)
    - Photograph-gay students at Virginia Tech, photographer: Alan Kim, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1991 January 27. (Frame 5:32)
    - Students want to shatter the myths by Daniel Howes, Roanoke Times and World-News, 1991 January 27. (Frame 5:33)
    - Invisible no more by Beth Macy, undated. (Frame 5:34)